A Guide to the William Newton Hale Papers 1951-1954
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Architectural Drawings
  - Lee Armentrout Residence, 13 Old Farm Road, Bellair 1953, 7 sheets (Folder 6)
  - Mrs. A. P. Mason Residence, Gordonsville n.d., 4 sheets (Folder 7)
  - Brizzolara n.d., 2 sheets (Folder 7)
  - Bellair Mailboxes n.d., 2 sheets (Folder 7)
  - William T. Stevens Residence, Bellair; alterations 1951, 4 sheets (Folder 7)
  - "Preliminary Study-A Laboratory for the Virginia Corporation;" (see Ciglia Corporation) n.d., 1 sheet (Folder 7)
  - W. C. Dorsey Residence; alterations 1951, 10 sheets (Folder 7)
  - James Dunlap Residence, 24 Canterbury Road, Bellair n.d., 2 sheets (Folder 7)
  - Watercolor Sketches; student work c. 1939, 36 sheets (Folder 8)
  - Student Design Exercises c. 1939-1943 (Folder 9)
    - Arch Design A
      - "A School for Adult Education"; Class A, Problem 1
    - Arch Design B
      - "A Lodge for Mountain Climbers"; Class B, Sketch I
      - "A Bandshell"; Class B, Sketch IV
      - "An Overland Bus Station"; Class B, Sketch IV
      - "A Civilian Aeronautics School"; Class B, Project I
      - "A Building Products Display Center"; Class B, Project IV
      - "A Country Newspaper Plant"; Class B, Project V
    - Arch Design B-I
      - "A Tennis Club"; Class B-I, pledged [unnamed military building]; Class B-I, pledged
      - "A City Movie Theater"
    - Arch Design B II?
      - [Interiors, Early Virginia Meeting House]
      - "A Caddy House"
      - "An Author's Studio"
    - Arch Design B 3
      - "Apartment House"
      - "Facade for a High School"
      - "A Ballroom for a Country Club"
    - [Unknown Design Class]
      - [modern house], 3 sheets
    - Arch. Construction
      - Various exercises, 3 sheets
  - William N. Hale Residence #2, 1923 Meadowbrook Road 1947, 5 sheets (Folder 10)
  - J. Robert Neal Residence, addition; 1923 Meadowbrook Road (former Hale residence) 1954, 18 sheets (Folder 10)
  - Bickers Residence, Stanardsville 1953, 4 sheets (Folder 11)
  - Milliman Residence, Crozet VA; interior cabinetry n.d., 3 sheets (Folder 11)
  - Mr. & Mrs. Neil Hevener Residence n.d., 1 sheet (Folder 11)
  - Unidentified House plan n.d., 1 sheet (Folder 11)
  - Unidentified House plan n.d., 1 sheet (Folder 11)
  - Unidentified House plan n.d., 1 sheet (Folder 11)
  - "Spottswood Road" House n.d., 3 sheets (Folder 11)
  - Joseph Pace Residence, Bellair, (unbuilt?) n.d., 2 sheets (Folder 11)
  - James Murray Residence; alterations 1952, 9 sheets (Folder 11)
  - Salvation Army Building, Charlottesville; addition & alterations; sketch plans 1951-1953, 15 sheets (Folder 12)
  - Salvation Army Building, Charlottesville; addition & alterations; working drawings 1951-1953, 21 sheets (Folder 12)
  - Salvation Army Building, Charlottesville; addition & alterations; working drawings 1951-1953, 8 sets of prints; 37 sheets (Folder 13)
  - Daniel Poor Residence; alterations 1951, 5 sheets (Folder 14)
  - Tremain Residence, Farmington; alterations n.d., 4 sheets (Folder 14)
  - J. T. Henley Residence, Crozet; alterations 1953, 3 sheets (Folder 14)
  - Robert Carlyle Barrit- Showcase n.d., 1 sheet (Folder 14)
  - Martin Plumbing Building; alterations 1951, 3 sheets (Folder 14)
  - Hillside House n.d., 3 sheets (Folder 14)
  - W. C. Hutchinson Residence, Brookley Farm n.d., 2 sheets (Folder 14)
  - Ciglia Residence and Business 1953, 4 sheets (Folder 14)
  - Angus McDonald Residence, Rapidan, Virginia 1945, 1 sheet (Folder 14)
  - S. C. Miller Residence 1952, 1 sheet (Folder 14)
  - Donald Stevens Motor Court; "Gallery Courts" 140 Emmet Street n.d., 2 sheets (Folder 15)
  - Donald Stevens Residence, Cismont; alterations (March 1952) 1952, 5 sheets (Folder 15)
  - Donald Stevens Residence, Cismont; alterations (January 1952) 1952, 8 sheets (Folder 15)
  - Donald Stevens Cottage n.d., 2 sheets (Folder 15)
  - Charles Barham Business; alterations 1954, 10 sheets (Folder 16)
  - Barham Store 1952, 6 sheets (Folder 16)
  - Barham Residence; ("Bellair #1, Rockstraw buyer, 19 Old Farm Road (see Whitehill residence, related design) 1953, 6 sheets (Folder 16)
  - J. Fulton Bishop Residence, 6 Canterbury Road, Bellair n.d., 9 sheets (Folder 17)
  - Mr. & Mrs. William Brown Residence, Scottsville; alterations 1952-1953, 10 sheets (Folder 17)
  - Mrs. Joseph Carter Residence; alterations n.d., 2 sheets (Folder 17)
  - Mrs. Joseph Carter Residence; alterations to basement n.d., 2 sheets (Folder 17)
  - "Windie Knowe"; measured drawings 1944, 2 sheets (Folder 18)
  - Gadsby's Tavern, Alexandria; "Detail of Tap and Bar" by Milton Grigg 1933, 1 sheet (Folder 18)
  - Hollymead; "Detail of Dormers;" by Milton Grigg 1940, 1 sheet (Folder 18)
  - Mrs. Nelson Brooks Residence; "Mantel Detail for Bedroom #1;" by Milton Grigg 1940, 1 sheet (Folder 18)
  - David Smith Residence 1952, 19 sheets (Folder 19)
  - David Smith Residence 1952, 13 sheets (Folder 20)
  - Smith Farm Storage Buildings 1952, 2 sheets (Folder 20)
  - David Smith Residence 1952, 8 sheets (Folder 20)
  - Dr. & Mrs. V. H. Marshall Residence 1951, 4 sheets (Folder 21)
  - Mrs. Nancy Clay Hancock Servants House 1951, 10 sheets (Folder 21)
  - Arthur Whitehill Residence, Chapel Hill, N.C. 1952-1953, 12 sheets (Folder 22)
  - Horween Residence; alterations 1952, 15 sheets (Folder 22)
  - Cushman Business Offices; sketch plans 1951, 7 sheets (Folder 23)
  - Cushman Business Buildings 1951, 8 sheets (Folder 23)
  - Cushman Business Buildings; retail and motel projects 1951-1952, 6 sheets (Folder 23)
  - Cushman Residence Additions 1951-1952, 10 sheets (Folder 23)
  - Alger Residence, 2 Lake Road, Farmington, Virginia 1952-1953, 35 sheets (Folder 24)
  - Alger Residence, Farmington, Virginia 1952-1953, 25 sheets (Folder 25)
  - Alger Residence, Farmington, Virginia 1952-1953, 39 sheets (Folder 26)
  - Commonwealth Courts, Ivy Road 1954, 39 sheets (Folder 27)
  - Commonwealth Courts 1954, Oversize drawings folded, 4 sheets (Folder 27)
  - Esso Service Station for J. Deering Danielson 1952, 26 sheets (Folder 28)
  - Howard Johnson Restaurant Alterations; 130 Emmet Street 1952, 13 sheets (Folder 29)
  - Mount Olivet Church Alterations 1951-1952, 8 sheets (Folder 29)
  - Howard Johnson Restaurant blueprint working drawings by Joseph A. Cicco for Howard Johnson Company 1946, 32 sheets (Folder 30)
  - J. Deering Danielson Restaurant Building, Ivy Road, (now University Police Station and Visitors Center) 1951-1952, 17 sheets (Folder 31)
  - Farmington Country Club; blueprint working drawings; "Thomas Stevens George, Jr.- Delineator" 1938, 5 sheets (Folder 31)
  - Farmington Country Club Alterations; blueprint working drawings by Marshall Wells 1945, 4 sheets (Folder 31)
  - Farmington Country Club Additions; sketch n.d., 2 sheets (Folder 31)
  - Sketchley Residence; original working drawings 1953, 4 sheets (Folder 32)
  - Sketchley Residence; prints 1953, 5 sets of 4; 20 sheets (Folder 32)
  - Topographic Map of Lot 32, Block. 4, Rugby Subdivision (Sketchley property) 1953, 1 sheet (Folder 32)
  - Unknown plan studies n.d., 20 sheets (Folder 33)
  - Studies of Molding Profiles and Other Details, Williamsburg n.d., 9 sheets (Folder 33)
  - Print, kitchen details, "Baldwin Job" n.d., 1 sheet (Folder 33)
  - Print, plan and elevation, Unknown House n.d., 1 sheet (Folder 33)
  - Print, preliminary drawing, Male Residence n.d., 1 sheet (Folder 33)
  - H. B. Thomas Residence, Orange VA 1951, 12 sheets (Folder 33)
  - Holloran Residence ("Tufton") Alterations 1952, 7 sheets (Folder 34)
  - Haynes Settle Residence, Cherry Avenue 1954, 3 sheets (Folder 34)
  - Holladay Residence, 34 Old Farm Road n.d., 1 sheet (Folder 34)